.　　　替　.
.　　　替扌.
.　　　替换.
.属　　替换.
.属和　替换.
.属和弦替换.
和Myles一起学音乐
属和弦替换
属七和弦向下行纯五度解决
the dominant seventh chord resolving down a perfect fifth
是音乐中非常有效地和声移动方式
is the most powerful harmonic gesture in music
我们都听过这种形式
we all know the sound
超级无敌移动法
the ultimate resolution
当然这是个非常常见而直白的声音了
of course it's also an extremely common
and straightforward sound
接下来我将展示如何把这个主意变得更加
I'm going to show you how to make this idea much more
（有趣）
因崔斯汀
Interesting
但首先让我们先研究一下这个和弦本身
but first we need to take a closer look
at the chord itself
属七和弦在大和弦的五度位置自然的出现
the dominant seventh chord occurs naturally
on the fifth degree of a major scale
结构上它就是个大和弦加一个小七度
structurally it's a major triad
plus a minor seventh
这个结构包含了一个非常特别的音程
now this structure contains a very special interval
这个和弦的大三度和小七度之间间隔六个半音
there are six semitones between
the major third and the minor seventh of the chord
这是一个相当不和谐的音程
this is a powerfully dissonant interval
被称为三全音
known as the tritone
把这个三全音当作属七和弦的骨架的话
think of the tritone as the backbone
of the dominant seventh chord
这个固有的不和谐音就是
this inherent dissonance is
这个和弦听起来是想要解决的原因了
one of the reasons these chords
usually sound like they really want to resolve
尤其是向其向下的纯五度解决
specifically to the chord a perfect fifth below them
*向上纯四度也一样
在 G7 和弦中包含的三全音
the notes in G7 tritone
B 和 F 完美的向 C 大和弦中的 C 和 E 解决
B and F resolve perfectly to
the C and the E in C major
——即其下方的纯五度和弦
the chord a perfect 5th below
这里开始将会变得有趣起来
okay here's where it gets interesting
由于三全音就是半个八度的音程
since tritones are exactly half of an octave
故他们是转位对称的
they are inversionally symmetrical
换句话说你对三全音进行转位
in other words when you invert a tritone
你最终得到的还是三全音
you end up with the same tritone
如果你想一想的话这就意味着
if you think about it this means
任意给定一个三全音那它们一定
any given tritone really exists in
存在于两个不同的属七和弦，并且
two different dominant seventh chords and
这两个和弦正好相距一个三全音的音程
those chords will have to be a tritone away from each other
并且，由于三全音在这个和弦功能中的重要性
and since the tritone is such a big part
of the function of these chords
我们应该有两个不同的属七和弦想要向同一个地方解决
we should have two different
dominant seventh chords that both want
我们应该有两个不同的属七和弦想要向同一个地方解决
to resolve to the same place
欢迎来到 三全音替换
welcome to tritone substitution
好的一起来看
okay let's see
属七和弦 G7 中一个三全音音程的和弦应该是 Db7 和弦
the dominant 7th chord
a tritone away from G7 would be Db7
我们只需要把 B 记作 Cb
we just need to re spell our B as a C flat
然后可以看出他们共有一个三全音只是转位了
and we can see they do indeed
shared the same tritone only inverted
G7 和弦中的大三度音成为了 D♭7 和弦中的小七度，反之亦然
what was originally the major 3rd of G7 became
the minor 7th of D flat 7 and vice-versa
脑子没跟上的话不必担心
okay don't worry if you didn't quite follow all that logic
总结起来是这样的：
here's the bottom line
如果我们要向某个目标和弦移动
if we want to target a certain chord
比如 C 和弦的话
for example C
我们就可以使用属七和弦
we can do so using the dominant 7th chord
即上行纯五度的 G7 和弦
a perfect fifth above it which is G7
或者我们也可以使用距其半音的属七和弦
or we can use the dominant 7th chord a half step above it
D♭7 和弦
D flat 7
这个例子中 D♭7 就是一个属音替换和弦
in this case D flat 7 would be a substitute dominant chord
或称三全音代理（三全音替换）和弦
or tritone sub
实际上这样做和原来的方案来讲功能上是一样的
it does basically the same job as its more common counterpart
但这样做更具色彩
but in a more colorful way
顺便
by the way
我们使用这些箭头来标记属和弦的移动
we use these arrows to indicate dominant resolutions
实线箭头表示一个属七和弦向其下方的纯五度解决
a solid arrow for a dominant seventh chord resolving down a perfect fifth
虚线则表示属七和弦向其下方半音的和弦解决
and a dotted arrow for a dominant seventh chord resolving down a half step
所以我们可以用实线或虚线箭头指向任何和弦
so we can use a solid arrow or a dotted arrow
to lead into almost any chord
这里是一个使用了两种类型的属和弦移动方式的和弦进行
here's a progression that uses both types of dominant resolutions
现在我们熟知了基本的概念
now that we have the basic concept down
是时候进入新的纪元了
It's time to take to the next level
使用二级小七和弦引入五级七和弦是很常见和有效的方案
it's very common and effective for the
two minor seven chord to lead into the five seven chord
这个情况下
in this situation
二级小七和弦被称作关系二级和弦
two minor seven is what's called a related two chord
也就是小七和弦向下一个纯五度音程
that's a minor 7th chord leading down a perfect fifth
转到一个属七和弦
into a dominant seventh chord
我们用方括号表示这种关系
we analyze this relationship with a bracket
所以我们现在有了一个方括号跟着一个箭头了
so we have a bracket leading into an arrow
听起来像这样
and it sounds like this
但是关联二级和弦并不需要总是该调内的二级和弦
but related two chords don't have to be the actual two chord in the key
我们可以使用方括号关系来替换任意属七和弦
we can use this bracket relationship to
set up any dominant 7th chord
让我们看看如果我们
let's see what happens when we add
把关联二级和弦添加到下属五级七和弦前会发生什么
a related two chord to our subV7
D♭7 和弦下行纯五度的小七和弦
the minor 7th chord a perfect fifth above D flat seven
即 A♭-7 和弦
would be A flat minor seven
一个在 C 大调中期望之外的和弦
a very unexpected chord in the key of C major
所以这个和弦一开始听起来会感觉很奇怪
so this chord will sound puzzling at first
但听下去就会觉得效果的确很好
but once you hear where it's going it works really well
让我们开始变得更奇怪吧
now let's get weird
如果我们把用来连接 D♭7 的关系二级和弦
what if we take D flat seven related two chord
使之来连接 G7 和弦会怎样
but swap G7 back in
现在我们有了一个小七和弦
now we have a minor 7th chord
向下半音解决到一个属七和弦
leading down a half step into a dominant seventh chord
被称为替换二级和弦（相关二级七和弦代理）
this is called a substitute related two chord
由虚线方括号标识
indicated by a dotted bracket
那用虚线方括号导向虚线箭头怎么样
and how about a dotted bracket with the dotted arrow
你还可以使用各种奇怪姿势把这些箭头和括号链起来
you can even start chaining together and
combining these brackets and arrows
你还可以使用各种奇怪姿势把这些箭头和括号链起来
in all sorts of wild ways
就有了无限多的可能性
the possibilities are endless
这里是一个小例子
here's a little example
所以属和弦替换
so substitute dominance and related two
能给你一些很酷炫的效果
can give you some pretty far-out sounds
但由于这些和弦有着很明确的功能
but since these chords have such clear function to them
这导致效果听起来会比你期望的更好
they tend to sound a little more palatable than you might expect
听起来有一种半音体系的味道
given the amount of chromaticism involved
这是我的“随心讲”小课堂
this is one of my go-to techniques
我会寻找一些有趣但又不难理解的内容来讲
if I'm looking for something interesting
but not too difficult to listen to
如果你喜欢这个视频请（在油管）订阅我的频道
if you enjoyed this video please subscribe
也别忘了看看我的 Patreon 页面
also check out my patreon page
这个频道的目的是
the purpose of this channel
向世界提供免费的音乐教学视频
is to offer free music education to the world
你的贡献能使之成为可能
and your contributions make that possible
苟利祸福
祝你好运，玩的开心
good luck, have fun